<?xml version='1.0'?>
<event>
    <eventid>199312050002</eventid>
    <iyear>1993</iyear>
    <imonth>12</imonth>
    <iday>5</iday>
    <extended>0</extended>
    <country>15</country>
    <country_txt>Austria</country_txt>
    <region>8</region>
    <region_txt>Western Europe</region_txt>
    <provstate>Vienna (State)</provstate>
    <city>Vienna</city>
    <vicinity>0</vicinity>
    <summary>12/05/1993: Mayor Helmut Zilk of Vienna was seriously wounded when a letter bomb exploded when Zilk, age 66, opened his mail after returning home from a trip to Switzerland. He was taken to a hospital in Vienna where he had two fingers on his left hand amputated. Police arrested two right-wing extremists, Peter B. and Alexander W., for mailing the letter bombs.</summary>
    <crit1>1</crit1>
    <crit2>1</crit2>
    <crit3>1</crit3>
    <doubtterr>0</doubtterr>
    <multiple>1</multiple>
    <success>1</success>
    <suicide>0</suicide>
    <attacktype1>3</attacktype1>
    <attacktype1_txt>Bombing/Explosion</attacktype1_txt>
    <targtype1>2</targtype1>
    <targtype1_txt>Government (General)</targtype1_txt>
    <corp1>Mayor of Vienna</corp1>
    <target1>Helmut Zilk</target1>
    <natlty1>15</natlty1>
    <natlty1_txt>Austria</natlty1_txt>
    <gname>Unknown</gname>
    <motive>Possibly in protest of the programs to aid refugees from war-torn Yugoslavia</motive>
    <guncertain1>0</guncertain1>
    <individual>0</individual>
    <nperps>2</nperps>
    <nperpcap>2</nperpcap>
    <claimed>0</claimed>
    <compclaim>-9</compclaim>
    <weaptype1>6</weaptype1>
    <weaptype1_txt>Explosives</weaptype1_txt>
    <weapsubtype1>9</weapsubtype1>
    <weapsubtype1_txt>Letter Bomb</weapsubtype1_txt>
    <nkill>0</nkill>
    <nkillus>0</nkillus>
    <nkillter>0</nkillter>
    <nwound>1</nwound>
    <nwoundus>0</nwoundus>
    <nwoundte>0</nwoundte>
    <property>0</property>
    <ishostkid>0</ishostkid>
    <addnotes>At least 10 letter bombs were sent, four exploded and six were defused over a four-day period ending on December 6, 1993. All of the recipients were involved in programs to aid refugees from war-torn Yugoslavia or other parts of Eastern Europe. Zilk was regarded as a champion of minority rights and was instrumental in the recent opening of Vienna's first postwar Jewish museum. Both accused perpetrators have ties to neo-Nazi groups in Germany. This was one of 4 related attacks (199312030001-02, 199312040001, 199312050002).</addnotes>
    <scite1>“Mail Bomb in Austria Hits Mayor; Anti-Refugee Groups Suspected in Attack,” St. Louis Post-Dispatch, December 6, 1993.</scite1>
    <scite2>Maud S. Beelman, “Vienna Mayor Injured in Fifth Letter Bomb Attack in Three Days,” The Associated Press Worldstream, December 5, 1993.</scite2>
    <scite3>Ken Olsen, “Alert Clerk, Border Guards and Luck Led to Letter Bomb Arrests,” The Associated Press, December 10, 1993.</scite3>
    <dbsource>CETIS</dbsource>
    <INT_LOG>-9</INT_LOG>
    <INT_IDEO>-9</INT_IDEO>
    <INT_MISC>0</INT_MISC>
    <INT_ANY>-9</INT_ANY>
</event>